Brendan Houng

Contact Information

Mobile: 0433 507 750 Email: brendan.houng@gmail.com

Web: linkedin, CV, google scholar

Summary

Data Scientist at Ambulance Victoria. Engaged in analytic sprints to provide insights to internal customers and executive management, communicating complex concepts through visualisations and statistical analyses. Previously, 12 years of combined experience as an applied economist in public policy research and in competition regulation.

Education

Ph.D. Economics University of Melbourne (2018) B. Commerce/ B. Software Engineering University of Melbourne (2005)

Technical Skills

Statistics/Econometrics, Machine Learning, and Geospatial Mapping. R, Python, Stata, SQL, bash, RMarkdown & Jupyter notebooks, ggplot, matplotlib & d3. See for example R version of Microsoft's TrueSkill algorithm.

Work Experience

Insight Specialist, Ambulance Victoria (AV), Doncaster Melbourne, October 2018 - Present

Joined AV as part of their Analytics Uplift project to improve AV's advanced analytic capability. Engaged in 4-6 week analytic sprints to provide insights for internal customers and executive management using a Scrum Agile framework. Outputs have included: predictive modelling, interactive dashboards, clustering, visualisations and statistical analyses.

Research Officer, Melbourne Institute of Applied Economic & Social Research, University of Melbourne, January 2009 - August 2018

Conducted and collaborated on public policy research mostly in the area of Economics of Education for the Victorian Department of Education, and completed a PhD in Economics. Experienced in data analysis, report writing and presentations for academic and general audiences. Refer to CV for further details.

Graduate/Project Officer, Australian Competition & Consumer Commission, February 2006 - July 2008

Contributed to investigations of merger transactions after completing the graduate program in the telecommunications, energy and mergers branches at the Australian competition regulator. Analysed price data to assess the potential change in local competition arising from proposed transactions.

Last updated: May 4, 2019
Brendan Houng